

# Monisha Gunalan

Associate at Cognizant

moni.joyce94@gmail.com





Chennai, India



Passionate Software Developer with 4.11 years experience in Healthcare IT System development and automation. Seeking a job as SSIS/SQL Developer in a reputable IT company. I am a fast learner and have good efficiency in understanding and analyzing subject matters associated with the project and functional architectures of the work flows in the products/System involved.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Associate** 

Cognizant Technology Solutions

10/2020 - Present

Chennai, India

**Programmer Analyst** 

Cognizant Technology Solutions

02/2018 - 09/2020

Chennai.India

**Programmer Analyst Trainee**Cognizant Technology Solutions

02/2017 - 02/2018

Chennai, India

### **EDUCATION**

**B.E Electrical and Electronics Engineering** 

Vel Tech Owned By R.S Trust

08/2012 - 02/2016 CGPA: 7.9

Higher Secondary

Velammal Matric Hr. Sec. School

05/2011 - 04/2012

84.5%

SSLC

Velammal Matric Hr. Sec. School

05/2009 - 02/2010

90.4%

#### **SKILLS**

SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS)

SQL Server 2016

Crystal Report XI

SSRS

Web API

Postman

MS Office

C#.Net

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

Alignment Healthcare (Honored Citizens Choice Health Plan) - SSIS & SQL Developer (08/2017 - Present)

- Worked with a US based healthcare client to develop and enhance software applications for processing data and health insurance claims on .NET and VB.Net platforms.
- Project involves creating API and web pages to validate the claim details, member details and view the health plans. Using SSIS member details and claim details files are loaded into the database and reports are generated as per client requirements.
- Worked on onboarding new enrollments received by the client.
  Developed several SQL Server Integration Service (SSIS) packages to automate file processing.
- Writing optimized SQL server queries.
- Automated the file processing for audit files to reduce human effort by 80%.
- Involved in testing and validating the results doing Unit Testing, Integration and system testing.
- Been a part of daily Scrum meetings and Sprint planning.
- Worked on the enrollment process and it's related functionalities in portal, which facilitates the user to enroll members, Primary Care Physician change, check eligibility and other related service.
- Worked in Reporting services for automating reports and letters for the end-user.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Associate of the month (Oct - 2018 & Apr - 2019)

Recognized with awards for successful delivery of assignments within the stipulated time.

Best Performer 2020 (01/2020 - 12/2020)

Awarded as exceeded all the expectations in project for 2020 rating

#### **LANGUAGES**

English

Tamil

Full Professional Proficiency

Native or Bilingual Proficiency